<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publications on Homicide in Chicago 1870-1930</title>
    <link>/pubs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publications on Homicide in Chicago 1870-1930</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/pubs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>1000 Homeless Men (1914)</title>
      <link>/pubs/homeless/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pubs/homeless/</guid>
      <description>Contents  Table of Contents, Foreword (PDF - 1.16MB) Chapter 01: Introductory (PDF - 1.01MB) Chapter 02: Method of this Investigation (PDF - 1.30MB) Chapter 03: Physical Condition of Homeless Men (PDF - 0.90MB) Chapter 04: The Crippled and Maimed (PDF - 1.96MB) Chapter 05: Industrial Accidents in Relation to Vagrancy (PDF - 1.47MB) Chapter 06: The Insane, Feeble-minded, and Epileptic (PDF - 1.87MB) Chapter 07: Homeless Old Men (PDF - 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Manual of Criminal Law (1930)</title>
      <link>/pubs/manual/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pubs/manual/</guid>
      <description> Contents  Table of Contents, Editor&amp;rsquo;s Preface (PDF - .55MB) Chapter I: Criminal Law (PDF - 4.47MB) Chapter II: Procedural Law (PDF - 3.56MB) Index (PDF - .43MB)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anarchy and Anarchists (1889)</title>
      <link>/pubs/anarchy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pubs/anarchy/</guid>
      <description>###Anarchy and Anarchists (1889) Michael J. Schaack, Anarchy and Anarchists. A History of the Red Terror, and the Social Revolution in America and Europe. Communism, Socialism, and Nihilism in Doctrine and Deed. The Chicago Haymarket Conspiracy, and the Detection and Trial of the Conspirators. (Chicago, 1889) (F.J. Schulte and Co.).
The author of this long and detailed account of the investigations into the [Haymarket]() case was a member of the police force and a colleague of Inspector Bonfield, the police officer who led the police into the crowd at Haymarket on May 4, 1886.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crime Commission Report (1915)</title>
      <link>/pubs/ccreport/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pubs/ccreport/</guid>
      <description>The 1915 Crime Commission Report. This Report included statistical data, descriptions of judicial and legal institutions, and is a model of data collection. It is included here in its entirety.
####Contents * Table of Contents, Editor&amp;rsquo;s Preface (PDF - 1.67MB) * Chapter I: Statistics Relating to Crime in Chicago (PDF - 4.14MB) * Chapter II: Statistics Relating to Social Status of Offenders (PDF - 7.23MB) * Chapter III: Underlying Causes and Practical Methods for Preventing Crime (PDF - 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crime and the Civic Cancer-Graft (1922)</title>
      <link>/pubs/graft/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pubs/graft/</guid>
      <description>Judge Michael L. McKinley standing with a baseball bat on a street Judge M. L. McKinley, a former Chief Justice of the Criminal Court of Cook County, wrote Crime and the Civic Cancer – Graft, an expose of graft and corruption in the courts in 1923. As a former Chief Judge of the Criminal Court he could describe in detail just how the process of corrupting judges and prosecutors worked. The expose was published as a series of articles in the Chicago Daily News in 1923.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crimes of the Century (1998)</title>
      <link>/pubs/crimes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pubs/crimes/</guid>
      <description>Gilbert Geis and Leigh B. Bienen, Crimes of the Century (Boston, 1998). It analyzes five cases which seized the public imagination, and came to stand for more than the guilt or punishment of a single individual for a particular crime. The cases analyzed are: Leopold and Loeb; The Lindbergh Kidnapping; the Alger Hiss case; The Scottsboro cases; and the O.J. Simpson case.
Contents  Introduction (PDF - 0.98MB) Leopold and Loeb (1924) and the Cause of the Crime (PDF - 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hull House Maps and Papers (1895)</title>
      <link>/pubs/hullhouse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pubs/hullhouse/</guid>
      <description>The book Hull House Maps and Papers, published in 1895, is a series of essays and statistical information collected by Florence Kelley and her colleagues at Hull House, the settlement house at 335 South Halsted Street. The spectacular maps are modeled upon similar research on poverty and living conditions in London done by Charles Booth. The arresting beauty of these maps, and their economy of presentation of detailed information, have made them classics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If Christ Came To Chicago (1894)</title>
      <link>/pubs/christ/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pubs/christ/</guid>
      <description>William T. Stead, If Christ Came to Chicago (Chicago, 1894). It is a vividly written, highly perceptive account of life and politics in Chicago based upon the author’s visit to the city in 1893 -during a time of economic depression following the triumph of the [World’s Columbian Exposition](). William T. Stead, an erudite and well known British journalist and minister, interviewed notable public figures, as well as people who were poor, in jail, or involved in criminal activities or political graft.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Illinois Crime Survey (1929)</title>
      <link>/pubs/icc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pubs/icc/</guid>
      <description>The 1929 Illinois Crime Survey is a monumental study of the operation of the criminal courts, the juvenile courts, and of homicide in Chicago. Consisting of a series of separate reports, it remains a model of scholarship. The Illinois Crime Survey describes a system perceived to be in crisis as a result of the influence of organized crime and the corruption of judicial institutions. The Survey also offered detailed and valuable analyses of important criminal justice institutions, such as the Police, the Felony Courts, and the Juvenile Delinquent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JCLC Vol. 92 2002</title>
      <link>/pubs/journal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pubs/journal/</guid>
      <description>The Journal of Criminal Law and Criminology is a professional journal for legal scholars, criminologists, and social scientists published at the Northwestern University School of Law. It was founded in 1910 and has been in continuous publication at the Northwestern University School of Law since that time. Volume 92, Numbers 3 &amp;amp; 4 is a special issue devoted to articles and essays addressed to some aspect of the Chicago Historical Homicide Project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Not Wiser</title>
      <link>/pubs/notwiser/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pubs/notwiser/</guid>
      <description>Is the death penalty dying? This autobiographical essay offers observations on the application of capital punishment in three very different legal jurisdictions at three different time periods when, partially by happenstance and partially by design, she was a homicide researcher, a participant and an observer of- profound changes in the jurisdiction&amp;rsquo;s application of the death penalty.
Download entire document as PDF (146kb)
Contents  Abstract (p. 1) Introduction (p. 3) Illustrative Case No.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Police in America (1971)</title>
      <link>/pubs/pia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pubs/pia/</guid>
      <description> Contents  Table of Contents, Editor&amp;rsquo;s Preface (PDF - 0.17MB) Final Report Civil Service Commission City of Chicago Police Investigation (PDF - 5.29MB) Chicago Police System (PDF - 2.24MB) Discipline and Administration of the Police Department of the City of Chicago (PDF - 4.87MB)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The First Mayday: the Haymarket speeches (1980)</title>
      <link>/pubs/mayday/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pubs/mayday/</guid>
      <description>Bookjacket design - click on image to view full-size version
Contents  Table of Contents, Editor&amp;rsquo;s Preface (PDF - .77MB) Chapter I: Introduction (PDF - .21MB) Chapter II: The Fruit of the Sacrifice (PDF - .54MB) Chapter III: November 11th (PDF - .34MB) Chapter IV: November Eleventh (PDF - .79MB) Chapter V: Our Martyred Comrades (PDF - 2.97MB) Chapter VI: The Eleventh of November 1887 (PDF - .82MB) Chapter VII: Memorial Address (PDF - .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Negro in Chicago (1919)</title>
      <link>/pubs/negrochicago/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pubs/negrochicago/</guid>
      <description> Contents  Table of Contents (PDF - 1.79MB) Chapters 1 - 3 (PDF - 19.23) Chapters 4 - 6 (PDF - 32.59MB) Chapter 7 - 9 (PDF - 23.78MB) Chapter 10 - 11 (PDF - 14.95MB) Appendix (PDF - 2.10MB)  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>