<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Timeline of the City&#39;s History: 1919 on Homicide in Chicago 1870-1930</title>
    <link>/historical/timeline/1919/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Timeline of the City&#39;s History: 1919 on Homicide in Chicago 1870-1930</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/historical/timeline/1919/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicago Race Riot</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1919/397/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1919/397/</guid>
      <description>Chicago race riot, five policemen and one soldier with rifle standing on street corner
Chicago Daily News, Inc., photographer.
Created/Published ca. 1919 July-Aug
Summary Image of five policemen and one soldier with a rifle standing on a street corner during a race riot in the Douglas community area of Chicago, Illinois.
Notes This photonegative taken by a Chicago Daily News photographer may have been published in the newspaper.
Cite as: DN-0071298, Chicago Daily News negatives collection, Chicago Historical Society Reproduction Number: DN-0071298 Digital ID: ichicdn n071298</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicago Race Riot, Walgreen Drugs</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1919/403/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1919/403/</guid>
      <description>Chicago race riot, African American men standing in front of Walgreen Drugs, 35th and State
Chicago Daily News, Inc., photographer.
Created/Published ca. 1919 July-Aug
Summary Image of a crowd of African American men standing on the sidewalks in front of a Walgreen Drugs at the corner of 35th and South State Street in the Douglas community area of Chicago, Illinois, during a race riot. Police officers are standing at the forefront of the crowd.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>J.W. Ray Runs Daily News Marathon</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1919/88/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1919/88/</guid>
      <description>Informal full-length portrait of I. A. C. athlete J. W. Ray running on a sandy surface during a 1919 Chicago Daily News marathon in Chicago, Illinois, surrounded by a crowd. Buildings are visible in the background.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joe Loomis Injured</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1919/187/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1919/187/</guid>
      <description>Informal portrait of Joe Loomis, with bandages wrapped around his head, being held at the elbow by a policeman and standing on a sidewalk in Chicago, Illinois. He was associated with the Carr murder case.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Judge McKinley</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1919/149/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1919/149/</guid>
      <description>Image of Judge Michael L. McKinley of the Superior Court of Cook County sitting behind the judge&amp;rsquo;s bench in a courtroom in Chicago.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society. Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Judges Johnston, Baldwin, McGoonty</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1919/299/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1919/299/</guid>
      <description>Image of (left to right) lawyer Frank Johnston, Jr. Circuit Court Judge, Judge Jesse A. Baldwin, and Judge John P. McGoonty sitting behind a bench in a courtroom in Chicago, Illinois.
DN-0070927, Chicago Daily News negatives collection, Chicago Historical Society.
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sergeant Chris J. Haas</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1919/428/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1919/428/</guid>
      <description>Policeman Sergeant Chris J. Haas sitting on stool in front of house loading small gun
Chicago Daily News, Inc., photographer.
Created/Published 1919
Summary Informal portrait of policeman Sergeant Chris J. Haas loading a small gun and sitting on a stool in front of a house in Chicago, Illinois.
Notes This photonegative taken by a Chicago Daily News photographer may have been published in the newspaper.
Cite as: DN-0071249, Chicago Daily News negatives collection, Chicago Historical Society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>State and Madison Streets, The Busiest Corner in the World, on Armistice Day</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1919/271/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1919/271/</guid>
      <description>The clock indicates that the picture was taken at the moment when the great throng stood uncovered facing east in honor of those who fell in the World War. It is a far cry from the day in 1857 when James H. McVicker opened his first theatre on Madison Street between State and Dearborn Streets; and still a farther in the misty past is the day in 1845 when Chicago&amp;rsquo;s first public school was opened on the site of the Boston Store, then in School District Number 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strike at U.S. Steel Cooporation</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1919/398/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1919/398/</guid>
      <description>Strike at U.S. Steel Corporation, Gary, Indiana, with view of police and workers
Chicago Daily News, Inc., photographer.
Created/Published 1919
Summary Image of police and workers outside the U. S. Steel Corporation in Gary, Indiana during a steel mill strike in 1919.
Notes This photonegative taken by a Chicago Daily News photographer may have been published in the newspaper.
Cite as: DN-0071471, Chicago Daily News negatives collection, Chicago Historical Society. Reproduction Number: DN-0071471 Digital ID: ichicdn n071471</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>