<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Crimes of the Century on Homicide in Chicago 1870-1930</title>
    <link>/crimes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Crimes of the Century on Homicide in Chicago 1870-1930</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/crimes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>1870: Harrison Street Police Station</title>
      <link>/crimes/harrison-street/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/crimes/harrison-street/</guid>
      <description>[Harrison Street Police Station circa 1900]() [Image of the lockup keeper sitting in a rocking chair outside a row of jail cells in the Harrison Street police station]() click on image to view photo details
This 1870 murder is the first case in the database. It offers an example of how the data was recorded by the police over the entire period. The Harrison Street Police station was the central police station, and the report of the killing at a railroad yard includes information about the victim and defendant typical of later records.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1876: Boy Kicked to Death</title>
      <link>/crimes/torchlight/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/crimes/torchlight/</guid>
      <description>![Girls Sewing in Chicago Sweatshop]() click on image to view photo details
Children were present on the street, especially children of the poor and the workers, in ways which we would not recognize.
View case details&amp;hellip;
Children not only lived on the streets, and played on the streets, but many children worked in factories, in sweatshops, and in illegal enterprises.
For further reading: Lives of Children (Florence Kelley website (including 32 photographs))</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1876: The Stabbed Sailor</title>
      <link>/crimes/sailor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/crimes/sailor/</guid>
      <description>![Chicago Daily Tribune cover story]() click on image to view photo details
Random killings of people who found themselves in an unpredictable place at an unpredictable time occur throughout this data base. Chicago&amp;rsquo;s centrality as a transportation hub attracted people from all over the country and the world.
View case details&amp;hellip;
Chicago was a central port, and the shipping trade was a major industry.
If a person without identification was killed, the family might not hear the news for years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1886: Haymarket Affair</title>
      <link>/crimes/haymarket/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/crimes/haymarket/</guid>
      <description>![Chicago Daily Tribune cover story]() ![The Anarchists]() click on image to view photo details
The name refers to a designated meeting place, a square where an open market used to be held near Des Plaines and bordered on Randolf Street, where on May 4, 1886, an historic armed confrontation took place between a group of anarchists and labor activists and more than 170 armed police officers, who had been assembled at the Des Plaines Police Station a half block away in anticipation of a riot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1887: Lunatic at Large</title>
      <link>/crimes/lunatic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/crimes/lunatic/</guid>
      <description>![Eugene Patrick Prendergast, photographed in the Cook County Jail]() click on image to view photo details
Killings by persons who were insane, deranged or temporarily incapacitated mentally occur throughout this data set. The standard for proving insanity was the McNaghten test, the standard being that the actor did not know what he was doing or did not know that it was wrong. This standard is still used in most American jurisdictions today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1889: Murder-Suicide</title>
      <link>/crimes/murder-suicide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/crimes/murder-suicide/</guid>
      <description>[Elizabeth Mize, Murder Victim]() click on image to view photo details
In a number of these cases the defendant killed his wife, or wife and children, and then killed himself, or attempted to kill himself. And there are some cases where a woman killed her husband or her children and then killed herself or attempted to kill herself.
View case details&amp;hellip;
View all cases where domestic violence was the cause of death</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1893: Mayor Carter Harrison</title>
      <link>/crimes/carter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/crimes/carter/</guid>
      <description>![Mayor Carter Harrison, photo courtesy the Chicago Historical Society]()
The assassination of Mayor Carter Harrison occurred immediately after he had given the closing address at the World Columbian Exposition on October 28, 1893. The Mayor was known as the Mayor of the Common Man, and much beloved. The mayor was shot in his home by Eugene Patrick Prendergast, whose sanity was immediately in question. After several mental examinations Prendergast was executed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1903: Police Chief Cut to Death</title>
      <link>/crimes/police-chief/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/crimes/police-chief/</guid>
      <description>![]() click on image to view photo details
Extraordinary and dramatic circumstances of homicide, such as these, offer an opportunity for investigation into original source materials. Did the newspapers of the day offer an explanation for these events? Was the homicide sparked by police corruption, or related to another incident of interracial conflict?
View case details&amp;hellip;
Who was George Ahoy, the Chief of Police? And where is Margan Park, or is it Morgan Park?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1908: An Accidental Anarchist</title>
      <link>/crimes/lazarus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/crimes/lazarus/</guid>
      <description>![]() ![]() ![]() click on image to view photo details
The killing of Lazarus Averbuch by Chief of Police George Shippy in 1908 brought together as victim and defendant a poor Russian Jewish immigrant, suspected of being an anarchist, and a Chief of Police with little patience for any radical political agitation, of the kind associated with anarchists. Mysteries remain as to the identity and allegiances of the victim, why he had come to the residence of the Chief of Police, and the motivation of the Police Chief and the credibility of his explanations for the killing of Averbuch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1910: Child Murderess: The Mary Radek Case</title>
      <link>/crimes/radek/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/crimes/radek/</guid>
      <description>![]() click on image to view photo details
Cases involving children as victims and defendants are found at all periods in the records. Some cases are accidental deaths; some are intentional. All raise special issues for legal determination.
View case details&amp;hellip;
The period saw the founding of the world’s first juvenile court in 1899 (JCLC p.641-705). The Mary Radek case is discussed in detail in an article included here.
The Progressives and the social movements associated with the settlement houses and civic reform generally paid a great deal of attention to children and the conditions in which they lived and worked.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1910: Wife Murder In Chicago</title>
      <link>/crimes/wife-murder/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/crimes/wife-murder/</guid>
      <description>![]() View video of Cynthia Grant Bowman, author of Wife Murder in Chicago: 1910-1930
As in all homicide data sets, for any period and in any country, a significant proportion of all homicides are domestic homicides. The largest part of these domestic homicides involve men killing women who are wives or domestic partners. A small fraction involve wives killing husbands.
View case details&amp;hellip;
See also: 1889: Murder-Suicide</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1912: Husband Set On Fire</title>
      <link>/crimes/mussao/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/crimes/mussao/</guid>
      <description>![]() click on image to view photo details
Killings in circumstances of domestic violence are a substantial fraction of this set of homicide records. The specific situations may be bizarre, or unusual, as in this case, but the patterns are similar to cases reported today.
View case details&amp;hellip;
For further reading: &amp;ldquo;I Loved Joe, but I Had to Shoot Him&amp;rdquo;
Homicides Among Chicago Families: 1870-1930
Wife Murder in Chicago: 1910-1930</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1919: The Race Riot</title>
      <link>/crimes/raceriot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/crimes/raceriot/</guid>
      <description>![]() ![]() click on image to view photo details
The Race Riot in Chicago in the summer of 1919 left 38 dead, including twenty three black men and boys; and 537 injured, of whom 342 were black, and hundreds homeless. Race riots in other Midwestern and northern cities took place about the same time, as social tensions were aggravated by economic and labor problems after the World War I armistice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1921: Accidental Shooting</title>
      <link>/crimes/accidental/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/crimes/accidental/</guid>
      <description>Deaths attributed to accidental shootings occur regularly throughout this set of cases. Some cases involve children, some involve quarrels in saloons or bars, or circumstances of domestic violence.
Gun accidents and gun deaths are typically recorded by the police as part of their regular record keeping (JCLC p.547-548, JCLC p.516). Records concerning the regulation of firearms during this period are contradictory, and the subject of academic research and debate (Article by Greg S.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1921: Killing By An Officer</title>
      <link>/crimes/officer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/crimes/officer/</guid>
      <description>![]() ![]() ![]() ![]() click on image to view photo details
Murders by police and of police officers constitute a significant percentage of the homicides in this data set. Police kill persons who flee or resist arrest, or in circumstances of civil disorder, in self defense, or in other situations. These cases have been separately identified, and much research remains to be done on this subject.
View case details&amp;hellip;
Other cases involving police officers as defendants</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1921: Strike In A Packing House</title>
      <link>/crimes/packinghouse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/crimes/packinghouse/</guid>
      <description>![]() click on image to view photo details
The stockyards and the meat packing industry played a prominent role in the history and economic development of Chicago during this period. The battles between labor and management were sporadic, continuing, hard fought and often bitter, as vast numbers of workers from abroad and from the American South and rural areas flocked to Chicago seeking work in the industry.
View case details&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1922: Union Squabble</title>
      <link>/crimes/squabble/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/crimes/squabble/</guid>
      <description>![]() ![]() ![]() ![]()
click on image to view case details
Killings in revenge or from passion occur throughout this set of cases. Each is the remnant of a feud or complicated story, whose circumstances are only hinted at in the records here. Additional research in contemporaneous sources might begin to untangle some of the history which preceded the homicide.
The ongoing struggles between labor organizers, business owners, and the attempts of local, state and federal governments to control strikes and regulate working conditions are one of the overarching dramas of this entire period.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1923: Death By Moonshine</title>
      <link>/crimes/moonshine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/crimes/moonshine/</guid>
      <description>![]() ![]() ![]() Click on image for more detail
The association of death and alcohol includes accidental deaths from illegally brewed alcohol, which may have been toxic, and deaths from excessive drinking, in addition to manslaughters and murders comitted by persons who had been drinking alcohol. Homicide researchers have long been interested in the connection between homicides, both accidental and intentional, and the use of alcohol, and the cases in this data set provide an opportunity to analyze the relationship between alcohol and homicide with a new empirical data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1923: Intra-Racial Murder</title>
      <link>/crimes/intraracial/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/crimes/intraracial/</guid>
      <description>![]() ![]()
The vast majority of murders in this data set occur between persons of the same race and ethnicity, with the exception of extraordinary eruptions of violence such as the Chicago Race Riots in 1919.
For this data set of more than 11,000 cases the breakdown of homicides by race is as follows: JCLC p.520-521. The coding protocols for race of victim and defendant are described at: JCLC p.543-546. Data on race of victim and defendant are also presented as Figures (JCLC p.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1923: Revenge</title>
      <link>/crimes/revenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/crimes/revenge/</guid>
      <description>![Alice Davis Sing, Accused Murderess]() click on image to view case details
Killings in revenge or from passion occur throughout this set of cases. Each is the remnant of a feud or complicated story, whose circumstances are only hinted at in the records here. Additional research in contemporaneous sources might begin to untangle some of the history which preceded the homicide.
view sample homicide
Cases such as these remind the reader that each record of a case is potentially the beginning of a journey leading to information, not just about the complicated set of social interactions which preceded the murder, but the story of how those events were treated by official actors, as the crime became a case in the legal system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1924: Leopold and Loeb</title>
      <link>/crimes/leopold/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/crimes/leopold/</guid>
      <description>![Photograph of Leopold and Loeb with their defense attorney, Clarence Darrow and two unidentified men]() For Chicago, the Leopold and Loeb trial was the crime of the century. A fourteen year old boy, Bobby Franks, was murdered by two young men, Nathan Leopold and Richard Loeb, both from wealthy and socially established Jewish families, simply to commit the perfect crime. At their trial, the famous Clarence Darrow conducted a defense based upon psychological testimony, and captured the attention of the nation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1925: People vs. Fisher</title>
      <link>/crimes/fisher/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/crimes/fisher/</guid>
      <description>This was one of the first cases tried in the new Cook County criminal court building at 26th and California Street. The victim, a bank security guard, and all of the defendants were African Americans. The crime, a killing during the robbery of the Franklin Trust and Savings Bank, occurred in the south side of Chicago. The defense and the prosecutors operated at a high level of professional competence, within the standards of the day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1926: Capone vs. McSwiggin</title>
      <link>/crimes/mcswiggin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/crimes/mcswiggin/</guid>
      <description>![]() click on image for enlarged view
The gangland murder of this seemingly blameless Assistant State’s Attorney outraged the public and generated criticism of law enforcement and the notorious gangs fighting in the Beer Wars (Illinois Crime Survey p.825-841). The case signified to the public and the press the inability of the courts and prosecutors to control the violence generated by organized crime, as rival factions sought to control the illegal supply of alcohol and other activities.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>