<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Timeline of the City&#39;s History: 1914 on Homicide in Chicago 1870-1930</title>
    <link>/historical/timeline/1914/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Timeline of the City&#39;s History: 1914 on Homicide in Chicago 1870-1930</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/historical/timeline/1914/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>BCleofonte Campanini</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1914/389/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1914/389/</guid>
      <description>Musical Director of the Chicago Opera, Cleofonte Campanini, and his wife, standing near a street lamp
Chicago Daily News, Inc., photographer.
Created/Published 1914 Nov.4.
Summary Portrait of Cleofonte Campanini, musical director of the Chicago Opera, with his wife. This image was taken upon their arrival in Chicago from Parma, Italy. They are standing near a street lamp, with several other people, including a police officer, around them. This image was probably taken in Chicago, Illinois.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boswell C.F. Smith</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1914/406/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1914/406/</guid>
      <description>Boswell C. F. Smith and Capt. John. J. Ryan, sitting in a room
Chicago Daily News, Inc., photographer.
Created/Published ca. 1914 July 11
Summary Informal portrait of Boswell C.F. Smith and police Captain John J. Ryan, sitting in a room. Ryan is holding some papers in his hands. This image was probably taken in Chicago, Illinois.
Notes This photonegative taken by a Chicago Daily News photographer may have been published in the newspaper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detective Stanley Birns</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1914/438/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1914/438/</guid>
      <description>Photograph of Detective Stanley Birns, standing in uniform
Chicago Daily News, Inc., photographer.
Created/Published ca. 1914 July 22
Summary Image of a portrait of Stanley Birns, a police detective. He is standing in uniform for a formal portrait. Detective Birns was killed on July 7, 1914 in a gun fight in the levee district. Another policeman, Joseph Merrill, was wounded. This image was probably taken in Chicago, Illinois.
Notes This photonegative taken by a Chicago Daily News photographer may have been published in the newspaper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Group Portrait of the Funkhauser Moving Picture Censorship Group</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1914/157/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1914/157/</guid>
      <description>Group portrait of Samuel A. Bloch and Miss Katherine F. Birmingham standing, with Miss Florence B. Kirk, Miss Eva Loeb, Miss C. F. Karr, and Miss Christine Field sitting in front of them in a room in Chicago, Illinois. They are members of the Funkhauser moving picture censorship group, which advocated censoring moving pictures.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ike Bloom</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1914/421/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1914/421/</guid>
      <description>Photograph of Ike Bloom, proprietor of notorious dance hall
Chicago Daily News, Inc., photographer.
Created/Published 1914 July 24
Summary Image of a portrait of Ike Bloom, the proprietor of Kreiberg&amp;rsquo;s, a notorious dance hall in the Levee district. This image was taken from a portrait that hung in the Police Station located at 210 West 22nd Street, in the 3rd District, 3rd Precinct in the Near South Side community area of Chicago, Illinois.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>James Colosimo</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1914/385/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1914/385/</guid>
      <description>Attorney Charles E. Erbstein and gangster James Colosimo (also known as Big Jim), sitting in a room
Chicago Daily News, Inc., photographer.
Created/Published 1914
Summary Informal portrait of Attorney Charles E. Erbstein and gangster James Colosimo, sitting in a room. Colosimo ran brothels and saloons in Chicago. He reputedly was murdered by Al Capone on May 11, 1920. This image was probably taken in Chicago, Illinois.
Notes This photonegative taken by a Chicago Daily News photographer may have been published in the newspaper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>James Franche</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1914/380/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1914/380/</guid>
      <description>Isaac Henagow murder case, reputed gangster James Franche and policeman walking across sidewalk
Chicago Daily News, Inc., photographer.
Created/Published 1914 Apr. 14
Summary Informal full-length portrait of reputed gangster James Franche and a policeman walking across a sidewalk away from a building with other policemen standing in the entrance toward an automobile parked along the street with onlookers standing on the sidewalk in the background in Chicago, Illinois. Franche, nicknamed, Duffy the Goat, confessed to murdering Isaac Henagow in Roy Jones Cafe, located at 2037 South Wabash Avenue in the Near South Side community area of Chicago, Illinois.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>John Rowe, Policeman and Shooting Victim</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1914/139/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1914/139/</guid>
      <description>Image of a portrait of John Rowe, a policeman who was shot and killed on August 7, 1914. This image was probably taken in Chicago.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
See related case
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kids on Cleveland Avenue in Chicago</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1914/91/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1914/91/</guid>
      <description>Image of a boy holding a girl on his back, with two smaller children nearby. This image was taken on Cleveland Avenue (formerly Milton Avenue) in the Near North Side community area of Chicago, Illinois. This street was one of four, including West Chicago, North Cambridge Avenue, and West Oak Street that were the boundaries of one of Chicago&amp;rsquo;s most overpopulated areas.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Police Captain Max Nootbaar</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1914/409/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1914/409/</guid>
      <description>Police Captain Max Nootbaar, sitting in a room
Chicago Daily News, Inc., photographer.
Created/Published 1914 July 21
Summary Portrait of Police Captain Max Nootbaar. He is sitting in a room, which includes a typewriter in the background. Nootbaar was appointed by Chief Gleason to head the levee district operations. This image was probably taken in Chicago, Illinois.
Notes This photonegative taken by a Chicago Daily News photographer may have been published in the newspaper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shoeless Boy on Cleveland Avenue</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1914/92/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1914/92/</guid>
      <description>Image of a shoeless boy, holding the hand of a bigger girl and standing on the sidewalk of Cleveland Avenue (formerly Milton Avenue) in the Near North Side community area of Chicago, Illinois. This street was one of four, including West Chicago, Cambridge Avenue, and West Oak Street that were the boundaries of one of Chicago&amp;rsquo;s most overpopulated areas.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simon Hogan</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1914/336/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1914/336/</guid>
      <description>Trumbull Murder Case, Simon Hogan, Alleged Murderer, Sitting in a Room
Chicago Daily News, Inc., photographer.
Created/Published 1914 Aug. 17
Summary Portrait of Simon Hogan, an African American accused of murdering Cottage Grove Station police officer George Trumbull at 26th and South State Streets. Hogan held siege against 52 policemen for two hours after the murder before he surrendered. He is sitting in a chair in front of a standing police officer and an unidentified man.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>South Federal St.</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1914/417/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1914/417/</guid>
      <description>Houses on South Federal Street, in the levee district
Chicago Daily News, Inc., photographer.
Created/Published 1914
Summary View of Houses on Federal Street, in the levee district. A particular address, 2117 South Federal Street, is noted on the image. Federal Street is located in the Armour Square community area of Chicago, Illinois.
Notes This photonegative taken by a Chicago Daily News photographer may have been published in the newspaper.
Cite as: DN-0063323, Chicago Daily News negatives collection, Chicago Historical Society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ayor Harrison, parting envoys</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1914/411/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1914/411/</guid>
      <description>Mayor Harrison speaking with parting envoys
Chicago Daily News, Inc., photographer.
Created/Published 1914 July 8.
Summary Group portrait of Mayor Harrison speaking with aldermen and other officials who were about to leave for a European study trip. The envoys included E.C. Carter, John D. Shoop, Bion J. Arnold, Edward H. Bennett, Angus Roy Shannon, John F. Wallace, John E. Wilkie, John W. Beckwith, W. Harrah (Committee Clerk) and Aldermen Ellis Geiger, Eugene Block, William J.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>