<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Timeline of the City&#39;s History: 1903 on Homicide in Chicago 1870-1930</title>
    <link>/historical/timeline/1903/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Timeline of the City&#39;s History: 1903 on Homicide in Chicago 1870-1930</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/historical/timeline/1903/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Chentung-Liang-Cheng, the Chinese Minister to the U.S</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1903/55/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1903/55/</guid>
      <description>Informal portrait of Chentung-Liang-Cheng, Chinese Minister to the United States, Spain and Peru, wearing traditional Chinese dress, standing on a stepstool next to a train, holding onto the train&amp;rsquo;s rail with his left hand. Two African American porters and two men wearing suits are standing around him. The image was taken at Union Passenger Station located on the northeast corner of South Canal and West Adams Streets in the Near West Side community area of Chicago, Ill.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicago City Railway strike arrest</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1903/296/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1903/296/</guid>
      <description>Image of police leading men toward a patrol wagon during the Chicago City Railway strike in Chicago, Illinois.
DN-0001472, Chicago Daily News negatives collection, Chicago Historical Society.
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Girls Sewing in Chicago Sweatshop</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1903/47/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1903/47/</guid>
      <description>Image of eight girls sitting and facing a narrow table, sewing by hand on material held in their laps, during a sweatshop inspection in Chicago, Illinois. The girls are all looking at the camera.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Image of an Effigy Hanging from a Cable Line</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1903/297/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1903/297/</guid>
      <description>Image of an effigy hanging from a cable line over a commercial street during the Chicago City Railway Strike in Chicago, Illinois. A railway car and pedestrians are visible on the street.
Courtesy of the Chicago Daily News negatives collection, Chicago Historical Society, DN-0001418.
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Railway Strike 1</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1903/341/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1903/341/</guid>
      <description>Police standing next to and climbing aboard railway cars during the Chicago City Railway Strike
Chicago Daily News, Inc., photographer.
Created/Published ca. 1903
Summary Image of police standing next to and climbing aboard railway cars during the Chicago City Railway Strike in Chicago, Illinois.
Notes This photonegative taken by a Chicago Daily News photographer may have been published in the newspaper.
Cite as: DN-0001378, Chicago Daily News negatives collection, Chicago Historical Society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Railway Strike 2</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1903/342/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1903/342/</guid>
      <description>Line of railway cars at Clark and West Madison Streets with police standing on the street nearby and in the cars during the Chicago City Railway Strike
Chicago Daily News, Inc., photographer.
Created/Published ca. 1903
Summary Image of a line of railway cars at Clark and West Madison Streets with police standing on the street nearby and in the cars during the Chicago City Railway Strike in Chicago, Illinois. Sign on the first car reads: Wentworth 69.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>State Street</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1903/261/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1903/261/</guid>
      <description>State Street in 1903, north from Adams Street, showing noon day crowds.
Courtesy of &amp;ldquo;Chicago and Its Makers&amp;rdquo; (Chicago: Felix Mendelsohn, 1929).
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Steamship</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1903/77/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1903/77/</guid>
      <description>View of the front of the steamship, City of Paris, and another steamship docked side by side at a wharf in Chicago, Illinois.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Welfare Line at the County Agent&#39;s Office</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1903/46/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1903/46/</guid>
      <description>People lining up to receive welfare at a window in the County Agent&amp;rsquo;s office in Chicago, Illinois. A man wearing a uniform is standing near the window.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Girls During Sweatshop Inspection</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1903/50/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1903/50/</guid>
      <description>Image of three girls standing near stacks of fabric and sewing machines during a sweatshop inspection in Chicago, Illinois. Two men wearing suits are standing with the girls, and a man wearing work clothes is visible in the background.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Woman at Railroad Depot</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1903/51/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1903/51/</guid>
      <description>Image of one woman carrying wooden planks in a lot outside a railroad depot in Chicago, Illinois. She is walking toward the camera, away from a railroad depot. A railroad car standing outside the depot, and several trains inside the depot are visible in the background.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>