<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Timeline of the City&#39;s History: 1905 on Homicide in Chicago 1870-1930</title>
    <link>/historical/timeline/1905/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Timeline of the City&#39;s History: 1905 on Homicide in Chicago 1870-1930</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/historical/timeline/1905/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Archer Avenue Bridge</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1905/20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1905/20/</guid>
      <description>View of the streetcar crossing the Archer Avenue Bridge over the South Branch of the Chicago River in Chicago, Illinois. The streetcar is approaching a curve in the tracks. The Archer Avenue Bridge, a trunnion bascule bridge, connected the McKinley Park and Bridgeport community areas.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crowd Outside the Mallers Building</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1905/361/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1905/361/</guid>
      <description>Crowd outside the Mallers Building during a bucket shop raid
Chicago Daily News, Inc., photographer.
Created/Published ca. 1905
Summary Image of a crowd outside the Mallers Building during a bucket shop raid in Chicago, Illinois.
Notes This photonegative taken by a Chicago Daily News photographer may have been published in the newspaper.
Cite as: DN-0002973, Chicago Daily News negatives collection, Chicago Historical Society. Reproduction Number: DN-0002973 Digital ID: ichicdn n002973</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elizabeth Mize, Murder Victim</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1905/133/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1905/133/</guid>
      <description>Head and shoulders portrait of Elizabeth Mize of Chicago, Illinois. The portrait was taken after her murder and shows her lying down with face in profile and her body covered with a sheet.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
See related case
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Judge George Kersten and Judge Green sitting at the judges&#39; bench in court</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1905/298/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1905/298/</guid>
      <description>Judge George Kersten and Judge Green sitting at the judges&amp;rsquo; bench in court
DN-0002259, Chicago Daily News negatives collection, Chicago Historical Society.
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Police Holding Two Men Related to the Alexandro Murder Case</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1905/57/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1905/57/</guid>
      <description>Image of police holding the arms of two men while a crowd of men and boys looks on in Chicago, Illinois. This image is related to the Alexandro murder case.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saloon Interior</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1905/29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1905/29/</guid>
      <description>Saloon interior showing the bar, five men sitting around a table in the foreground, a man standing holding a bottle and another man in the background leaning against the bar.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>State Street</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1905/269/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1905/269/</guid>
      <description>A view of State Street, north from Madison in 1905, when the old cable cars rattled along both streets.
Courtesy of &amp;ldquo;Chicago and Its Makers&amp;rdquo; (Chicago: Felix Mendelsohn, 1929).
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Telephones During a Bucket Shop Raid</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1905/362/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1905/362/</guid>
      <description>Telephones on chairs and on the floor during a bucket shop raid
Chicago Daily News, Inc., photographer.
Created/Published ca. 1905
Summary Image of telephones on chairs and on the floor during a bucket shop raid in Chicago, Illinois.
Notes This photonegative taken by a Chicago Daily News photographer may have been published in the newspaper.
Cite as: DN-0002971, Chicago Daily News negatives collection, Chicago Historical Society. Reproduction Number: DN-0002971 Digital ID: ichicdn n002971</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Chicago City Council Chamber</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1905/79/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1905/79/</guid>
      <description>Interior view of the city council chamber in Chicago, Illinois, showing aldermen at their desks, men sitting in the balcony above and a portion of the speaker&amp;rsquo;s rostrum visible in the foreground.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Federal Building and Chicago Post Office, Opened in 1905</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1905/249/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1905/249/</guid>
      <description>View shows the northwest corner of Jackson and Dearborn Streets. The Grand Pacific Hotel may be seen at the left and the Marquette Building at the right.
Courtesy of &amp;ldquo;Chicago and Its Makers&amp;rdquo; (Chicago: Felix Mendelsohn, 1929).
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Women and Children on Halstead Street</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1905/56/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1905/56/</guid>
      <description>Image of a group of children and women walking in a dirt street near a wagon, possibly as part of a Chicago Daily News Fresh-Air Fund outing in Chicago, Illinois. The group may be walking in Halsted Street.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Women and Men Sewing in Sweatshop</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1905/85/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1905/85/</guid>
      <description>Image of women and men sewing at various tables and sewing machines in the workroom of a sweatshop at 132 Maxwell Street in the Near West Side community area of Chicago, Illinois.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>