<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Timeline of the City&#39;s History: 1908 on Homicide in Chicago 1870-1930</title>
    <link>/historical/timeline/1908/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Timeline of the City&#39;s History: 1908 on Homicide in Chicago 1870-1930</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/historical/timeline/1908/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Andy Craig</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1908/363/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1908/363/</guid>
      <description>Andy Craig, gambler, looking to the side, sitting in a witness room
Chicago Daily News, Inc., photographer.
Created/Published 1908
Summary Head and shoulders portrait of Andy Craig, a gambler, sitting in a witness room in Chicago, Illinois. He is looking to the side.
Notes This photonegative taken by a Chicago Daily News photographer may have been published in the newspaper.
Cite as: DN-0052380, Chicago Daily News negatives collection, Chicago Historical Society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anti-Smoke League Meeting</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1908/24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1908/24/</guid>
      <description>Women gathered on the steps of a building.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gunness Murders</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1908/36/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1908/36/</guid>
      <description>Three men with shovels and forks standing and looking at the area where bodies were found on the Gunness farm in LaPorte, Indiana.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Harry Shippy, Associated with the Death of Anarachist Lazarus Averbuch</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1908/135/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1908/135/</guid>
      <description>Full-length portrait of Harry Shippy, sitting in a chair with a pillow behind his back, with a book resting on his lap and his arms crossed in front of his chest, in a room at Augustana Hospital at 2037 North Cleveland Avenue in the Lincoln Park community area of Chicago, Illinois. Harry Shippy, the son of Police Chief George M. Shippy, was wounded in an incident at Police Chief Shippy&amp;rsquo;s house that resulted in the shooting death of Lazarus Averbuch, an alleged anarchist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Image of the Dead Body of Lazarus Averbuch</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1908/13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1908/13/</guid>
      <description>Image of the dead body of Lazarus Averbuch held up in a chair by Captain Evans of the police department in Chicago, Illinois. Averbuch, an alleged anarchist, was shot and killed during his attempt to assassinate Police Chief George M. Shippy at the Shippy home.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
See related case
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Isadore Maron, an Alleged Anarchist</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1908/14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1908/14/</guid>
      <description>Three-quarter length portrait of Isadore Maron, an alleged anarchist, sitting in a room. Isadore Maron was questioned by police in relation to the incident during which Lazarus Averbuch, an alleged anarchist, was shot and killed at Police Chief George M. Shippy&amp;rsquo;s house in Chicago, Illinois.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
See related case
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Johann Most, Anarchist</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1908/15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1908/15/</guid>
      <description>Image of a head and shoulders portrait drawing of Johann Most, anarchist. This image was probably taken in Chicago.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lazarus Averbuch, deceased (front)</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1908/349/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1908/349/</guid>
      <description>Dead body of Lazarus Averbuch held up in a chair by Captain Evans of the police department, front view
Chicago Daily News, Inc., photographer.
Created/Published 1908 Mar. 2.
Summary Image of the dead body of Lazarus Averbuch held up in a chair by Captain Evans of the Chicago police department. Averbuch was an alleged anarchist who was shot and killed at Police Chief George M. Shippy&amp;rsquo;s house in Chicago, Illinois.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lazarus Averbuch, deceased (side)</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1908/347/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1908/347/</guid>
      <description>Dead body of Lazarus Averbuch held up in a chair by Captain Evans of the police department, side view
Chicago Daily News, Inc., photographer.
Created/Published 1908 Mar. 2.
Summary Image of the dead body of Lazarus Averbuch held up in a chair by Captain Evans of the police department in Chicago, Illinois. Averbuch, an alleged anarchist, was shot and killed during his attempt to assassinate Police Chief George M. Shippy at the Shippy home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Men in Belle Gunness&#39;s Basement</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1908/41/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1908/41/</guid>
      <description>Men standing in the basement of the ruins of the Mrs. Belle Gunness house in LaPorte, Indiana.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mrs. William Mooney, Wife of a Murdered Policeman</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1908/136/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1908/136/</guid>
      <description>Half-length portrait of Mrs. William Mooney, the wife of a policeman who was shot, sitting in a room in Chicago.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
See related case
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Police Chief George M. Shippy&#39;s Home</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1908/348/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1908/348/</guid>
      <description>Hallway and stairway inside the residence of Police Chief George M. Shippy, seen from the front door
Chicago Daily News, Inc., photographer.
Created/Published ca. 1908 Mar. 16
Summary Interior view, from the front door, of a stairway and hallway inside the residence of Police Chief George M. Shippy at 31 Lincoln Place in Chicago, Illinois. Harry Shippy, the son of the police chief, ran down this stairway during the altercation with Lazarus Averbuch, an alleged anarchist who was shot and killed inside this house.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ray Lamphere, Belle Gunness Murder Suspect</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1908/40/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1908/40/</guid>
      <description>Half-length portrait of Ray Lamphere, a murder suspect associated with the Belle Gunness murder mystery, sitting in a room in LaPorte, Indiana. Mrs. Belle Gunness, who was associated with affinity finding bureaus, was found to have caused several deaths in LaPorte, Indiana.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Samuel Gompers, President of the American Federation of Labor</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1908/10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1908/10/</guid>
      <description>Samuel Gompers, president of the American Federation of Labor, standing outside surrounded by a group of men.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thomas Chamales</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1908/364/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1908/364/</guid>
      <description>Thomas Chamales, owner of the Savoy Restaurant
Chicago Daily News, Inc., photographer.
Created/Published 1908 Feb. 8.
Summary Three-quarter length portrait of Thomas Chamales, owner of the Savoy Restaurant on the southwest corner of East Harrison Street and South Wabash Avenue, standing in a room in Chicago, Illinois.
Notes A portion of this photonegative taken by a Chicago Daily News photographer was published in the newspaper on Feb. 8, 1908.
Cite as: DN-0005551, Chicago Daily News negatives collection, Chicago Historical Society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unemployed Bulgarian Men in Chicago</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1908/45/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1908/45/</guid>
      <description>Image of a group of unemployed Bulgarian men standing outside a building in Chicago.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>