<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Labor, Social and Reform Movements on Homicide in Chicago 1870-1930</title>
    <link>/historical/movements/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Labor, Social and Reform Movements on Homicide in Chicago 1870-1930</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/historical/movements/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>1919 Race Riot</title>
      <link>/historical/movements/race-riot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/movements/race-riot/</guid>
      <description>View case details&amp;hellip; Learning From the Past, Living In the Present: Understanding Homicide in Chicago, 1870-1930 (pages 520-521) by Leigh B. Bienen &amp;amp; Brandon Rottinghaus
The Race riot in Chicago in the summer of 1919 left 38 dead, including twenty three black men and boys; and 537 injured, of whom 342 were black, and hundreds homeless. Race riots in other Midwestern and northern cities took place about the same time, as social tensions were aggravated by economic and labor problems after the World War I armistice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jane Addams and Hull House</title>
      <link>/historical/movements/hullhouse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/movements/hullhouse/</guid>
      <description>Jane Addams, speaking to a crowd upon her arrival at Union Depot. More information.      Mrs. Lucy E. Parsons, arrested during protest at Hull House. More information.      View Hull House Maps. More information.      Jane Addams. More information.    For more information:
 Hull House Maps and Papers (1895): Chapter X: The Settlement as a factor in the labor movement Editor&amp;rsquo;s Preface Urban Experience in Chicago: Hull-House and Its Neighborhoods, 1889-1963.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prohibition and Temperance (1920-1933)</title>
      <link>/historical/movements/prohibition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/movements/prohibition/</guid>
      <description>         For more information:
Journal of Criminal Law and Criminology:
 Volstead Act in 1919 (Pages 449-452). The 1929 Illinois Crime Survey Report (Pages 493-496). The 1929 Illinois Crime Survey. Part III - Organized Crime in Chicago: Chapter XX: The Rule of the Underworld: Torrio as Overlord. Chapter XXI: The Beer Wars. Chapter XXXII: Terrorization by Bombs.  See also&amp;hellip;
 Homicides where victim was drinking/drunk Homicides where one or more of defendants was drinking/drunk Homicides where both victim and defendant(s) were drinking/drunk Homicides that occurred in a drinking establishment Homicides involving illegal liquor or prohibition  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Railroad Strike (1877)</title>
      <link>/historical/movements/railroad-strike/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/movements/railroad-strike/</guid>
      <description>Labor unrest, strikes, and the violence associated with demonstrations and picketing, and riots, were phenomena not just in Chicago, but across the country and internationally during this period. In Chicago, a number of killings in the police files were associated with labor demonstrations, and many other killings in situations of civil unrest were not reported.
Confrontations between labor and management, and between labor activists and police and other armed authorities, had long been simmering as ongoing disputes over wages and hours, the safety of working conditions, and the laying off of workers and their replacement by lower wage irregulars during times of economic hardship.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Haymarket Affair (1886)</title>
      <link>/historical/movements/haymarket/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/movements/haymarket/</guid>
      <description>The name refers to a designated meeting place, a square where an open market was formerly held near Des Plaines and bordered on Randolph Street. There, on May 4, 1886, an historic armed confrontation took place between a group of Anarchists and labor activists and more than 170 armed police officers, who had been assembled at the Des Plaines Police Station a half block away in anticipation of a riot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working in Chicago (1870-1930)</title>
      <link>/historical/movements/working/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/movements/working/</guid>
      <description>This is an image of a boy holding a girl on his back, with two smaller children nearby. This image was taken on Cleveland Avenue (formerly Milton Avenue) in the Near North Side community area of Chicago. This street was one of four, including West Chicago, North Cambridge Avenue, and West Oak Street that were the boundaries of one of Chicago&#39;s most overpopulated areas. More information.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>