<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Timeline of the City&#39;s History: 1915 on Homicide in Chicago 1870-1930</title>
    <link>/historical/timeline/1915/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Timeline of the City&#39;s History: 1915 on Homicide in Chicago 1870-1930</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/historical/timeline/1915/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Anna Johnson and Marshall Hostetler - Associated with the Anna Johnson Murder</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1915/109/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1915/109/</guid>
      <description>Miss Anna Johnson and Marshall Hostetler. The photograph was probably taken in Chicago, Illinois, in association with the Anna Johnson murder case.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
See related case
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Charles Mellon, Associated with the Matters Case</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1915/100/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1915/100/</guid>
      <description>Charles Mellon, sitting in a courtroom.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Children of Charles H. Johnston, Secretary of the United Brick and Clay Workers&#39; Union</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1915/170/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1915/170/</guid>
      <description>Group portrait of the children of Charles H. Johnston, secretary of the United Brick and Clay Workers&amp;rsquo; Union, sitting on the steps of a dwelling in Chicago, Illinois. Police believed Johnston committed suicide.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chris Muller</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1915/371/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1915/371/</guid>
      <description>Wells Fargo robbery, Christ Muller, standing in a police station.
Chicago Daily News, Inc., photographer.
Created/Published 1915
Summary Image of Christ Muller, standing in a police station in Chicago, Illinois, with three unidentified men. He appears to be buckling his belt. A telephone is visible in the foreground. Muller was involved in a Wells Fargo robbery.
Notes This photonegative taken by a Chicago Daily News photographer may have been published in the newspaper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clothing Workers Conclude Strik</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1915/70/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1915/70/</guid>
      <description>Image of clothing workers who had been on strike in Chicago, Illinois, going back to work. They are standing around Sidney Hillman, President of the Garment Union. They are holding bouquets of flowers and small American flags.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clothing Workers Strike at City Hall</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1915/65/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1915/65/</guid>
      <description>Image of a throng of striking clothing workers in the corridor of City Hall at 121 North LaSalle Street in the Loop community area of Chicago, Illinois. The crowd of over 1,000 strikers jammed the hallways of city hall after they attempted to have a parade.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clothing Workers Strike on S. Green Street</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1915/73/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1915/73/</guid>
      <description>Image of clothing workers, on strike, gathered in front of the Art Metal Products Company, located at 508 South Green Street in the Near West Side community area of Chicago, Illinois. A group of the strikers are on a horse drawn cart, standing with their hats raised in the air.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coppersmith Apartment, Scene of a Double Murder</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1915/105/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1915/105/</guid>
      <description>Interior view of the Coppersmith apartment, where Mrs. Ella Coppersmith and her infant son John were murdered by a robber. Blood stains are visible on the floor in the foreground. This apartment was in a building located at 7100 South Lowe Avenue in the Englewood community area of Chicago.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
See related case
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detective Axel Jensen</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1915/383/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1915/383/</guid>
      <description>Detective, Axel Jensen, standing outdoors with buildings in the background
Chicago Daily News, Inc., photographer.
Created/Published ca. 1915 Jan. 6.
Summary Portrait of Axel Jensen, a detective from the Hudson Street Station in Chicago, Illinois.
Notes This photonegative taken by a Chicago Daily News photographer may have been published in the newspaper.
Cite as: DN-0063863, Chicago Daily News negatives collection, Chicago Historical Society. Reproduction Number: DN-0063863 Digital ID: ichicdn n063863</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eastland Disaster, Captain Harry Pederson</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1915/402/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1915/402/</guid>
      <description>Eastland disaster, Captain Harry Pederson, standing on the overturned hull with policemen
Chicago Daily News, Inc., photographer.
Created/Published ca. 1915 Aug. 11
Summary Portrait of Harry Pedersen, captain of the Eastland steamer, standing on the overturned hull of the boat in the Chicago River in the Loop community area of Chicago, Illinois, with policemen. He was indicted on charges of criminal carelessness.
Notes Images related to This photonegative taken by a Chicago Daily News photographer were published in the newspaper between July 24-August 13, 1915.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eastland Disaster, Crowd 2</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1915/442/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1915/442/</guid>
      <description>Eastland disaster, crowd standing behind police line on LaSalle Street looking south from Water Street
Chicago Daily News, Inc., photographer.
Created/Published ca. 1915 July 24
Summary Bird&amp;rsquo;s-eye view of crowd at the Eastland disaster, standing behind a police line on North LaSalle Street looking south from Water Street Market in the Loop community area of Chicago, Illinois. A straw boater hat is visible in the lower left corner of the image.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eastland Disaster, crowd</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1915/394/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1915/394/</guid>
      <description>Eastland disaster, crowd standing behind police line on LaSalle Street, for rent signs visible on left
Chicago Daily News, Inc., photographer.
Created/Published ca. 1915 July 24
Summary Bird&amp;rsquo;s-eye view of crowd at the Eastland disaster site, standing behind a police line on LaSalle Street looking south from Water Street Market in the Loop community area of Chicago, Illinois. Two for rent signs are visible on the building on the left side of the image.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eastland Disaster, girl&#39;s body</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1915/393/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1915/393/</guid>
      <description>Eastland disaster, rescuers hoisting girl&amp;rsquo;s corpse up to rescuers standing above on the steamer&amp;rsquo;s hull
Chicago Daily News, Inc., photographer.
Created/Published ca. 1915 July 24
Summary Image of rescuers hoisting a girl&amp;rsquo;s corpse up to other rescuers standing above them on the hull of the Eastland, an overturned steamer in the Chicago River in the Loop community area of Chicago, Illinois. A police officer appears to be holding his jacket in preparation to wrap the body in it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eastland Disaster, line</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1915/396/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1915/396/</guid>
      <description>Eastland disaster, people lined up outside the temporary morgue at the Second Regiment Armory
Chicago Daily News, Inc., photographer.
Created/Published ca. 1915 July 24
Summary Image of people lined up outside the Second Regiment Armory, which was used as a temporary morgue for victims of the Eastland disaster. Policemen are on site, standing near the line of people. The armory was located on West Washington Boulevard in the Near West Side community area of Chicago, Illinois.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eastland Disaster, stretcher</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1915/395/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1915/395/</guid>
      <description>Eastland disaster, men carrying corpse on a stretcher to a waiting hearse on cobblestone street
Chicago Daily News, Inc., photographer.
Created/Published ca. 1915 July 24
Summary Image of men carrying a corpse on a stretcher to a waiting hearse on a cobblestone street in the Loop community area of Chicago, Illinois. Signage in the background reads O&amp;rsquo;Donnells and Haven Steamer (?).
Notes Images related to this photonegative taken by a Chicago Daily News photographer were published in the newspaper between July 24-August 13, 1915.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emma Peterson Murder Case</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1915/445/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1915/445/</guid>
      <description>Emma Peterson murder case, Lake Street, Aurora, Illinois
Chicago Daily News, Inc., photographer.
Created/Published 1915 Feb. 26
Summary View of Lake Street in Aurora, Illinois, which was the location where Emma Peterson was found murdered. Peterson was thought to be the third victim of a serial killer who had also murdered Theresa Hollander and Jennie Miller.
Notes This photonegative taken by a Chicago Daily News photographer was published in the newspaper on February 26, 1915.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Florence Carsello Sitting on Policeman Martin Ernest&#39;s Lap</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1915/160/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1915/160/</guid>
      <description>Half-length portrait of Florence Carsello, a bombing victim, sitting on the knee of Martin Ernest, policeman from the Maxwell Street Station. An unidentified boy is sitting in the background. Florence&amp;rsquo;s family was the target of a bomb explosion in their home at 846 South Miller Street in the Near West Side community area of Chicago, Illinois. Florence had been buried under the debris, but was rescued by police detectives. The rest of the family also survived with minimum injuries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frances Fay West, Linked to an Attempted Bombing</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1915/113/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1915/113/</guid>
      <description>Portrait of Frances Fay West standing in a yard in Chicago, Illinois holding a dog in her arms. She planned to elope with a suitor, but her mother intervened. The suitor planted a bomb at the West&amp;rsquo;s home at 1639 West Van Buren in an attempt to harm Mrs. West.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Garmet Workers Riot Against Police</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1915/67/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1915/67/</guid>
      <description>Image of striking garment workers and policemen, scuffling in Chicago, Illinois. Text on image reads, &amp;lsquo;Riot between garment workers and police.&amp;rsquo; A sign that reads &amp;lsquo;Tuxedo&amp;rsquo; is visible in the background, as is an advertisement for Roy Royal.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>George (Peanut) Natzke</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1915/177/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1915/177/</guid>
      <description>Portrait of George (Peanut) Natzke, sitting in a room in Chicago, Illinois. Natzke was accused of killing Charles Petzel, a mailman, when he came to the aid of Mabel Carr.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
See related case
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Henry R. Pontorno&#39;s Bank</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1915/343/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1915/343/</guid>
      <description>Henry R. Pontorno&amp;rsquo;s bank at 154 West 22nd Street
Chicago Daily News, Inc., photographer.
Created/Published 1915 Feb. 19
Summary Exterior view of Henry R. Pontorno&amp;rsquo;s bank at 154 West 22nd Street in the Near South Side community area of Chicago, Illinois. Pontorno claimed he had been robbed of 9,500 dollars, but the police were skeptical of his story.
Notes An image related to this photonegative taken by a Chicago Daily News photographer was published in the newspaper on February 19, 1915.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>James Ryan</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1915/390/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1915/390/</guid>
      <description>Egan and O&amp;rsquo;Brien graft trial, a clairvoyant, James Ryan, sitting in an office
Chicago Daily News, Inc., photographer.
Created/Published 1915 July 23
Summary Portrait of James Ryan, a clairvoyant, sitting in an office in Chicago, Illinois. Filing cabinets and stacks of books are visible in the background. Ryan was a witness in the Egan and O&amp;rsquo;Brien fraud case.
Notes An image related to this photonegative taken by a Chicago Daily News photographer was published in the newspaper on July 23, 1915.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jane Addams</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1915/388/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1915/388/</guid>
      <description>Jane Addams, sitting in an automobile in Chicago, Illinois
Chicago Daily News, Inc., photographer.
Created/Published 1915 July 22.
Summary Portrait of Jane Addams (1860-1935), sitting in an automobile in Chicago, Illinois. A policeman on horseback is visible in the background. Addams, the founder of Hull House in Chicago, had traveled to the Netherlands for an international women&amp;rsquo;s peace conference and throughout Europe to discuss peace issues with world leaders and then gave a lecture at the Auditorium Building on her findings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jane Addams, Speaking to a Crowd Upon Her Arrival at Union Depot</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1915/281/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1915/281/</guid>
      <description>Image of Jane Addams, speaking to a crowd upon her arrival at Union Depot in Chicago, Illinois. Addams, the founder of Hull House in Chicago, had traveled to the Netherlands for an international women&amp;rsquo;s peace conference and throughout Europe to discuss peace issues with world leaders and gave a lecture at the Auditorium Building about her findings.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>John Kovich</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1915/377/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1915/377/</guid>
      <description>John Kovich with baby, sitting in a room, with policeman and woman in background
Chicago Daily News, Inc., photographer.
Created/Published ca. 1915 Mar. 25
Summary Portrait of John Kovich with a baby, sitting in a room near a stove. A policeman is standing in the doorway, and a woman is behind Kovich. This image was probably taken in Chicago, Illinois.
Notes This photonegative taken by a Chicago Daily News photographer may have been published in the newspaper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lieutenant McCaulay</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1915/407/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1915/407/</guid>
      <description>Lieutenant McCaulay holding Richard Lillard in his lap, Harrison Street police station
Chicago Daily News, Inc., photographer.
Created/Published ca. 1915 Sept. 22
Summary Image of Lieutenant McCaulay of the Harrison Street police station in Chicago, Illinois, holding Richard Lillard in his lap.
Notes This photonegative taken by a Chicago Daily News photographer may have been published in the newspaper.
Cite as: DN-0065180, Chicago Daily News negatives collection, Chicago Historical Society. Reproduction Number: DN-0065180 Digital ID: ichicd n065180</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mabel Carr, Associated with the Charles Petzel Murder Case</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1915/118/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1915/118/</guid>
      <description>Portrait of Mabel Carr, sitting in a room in Chicago, Illinois. She was involved in the Charles Petzel murder case.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
See related case
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Man Leans Out Train Car Window</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1915/84/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1915/84/</guid>
      <description>Portrait of man leaning out of a window on train car no. 271 during a street car strike in Chicago, Illinois. The train car is alongside a station platform.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Man on Bike with Umbrella</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1915/78/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1915/78/</guid>
      <description>Image of a man holding an umbrella while riding a bike along an street in the rain during a street car strike in Chicago, Illinois. Street car tracks are visible on the street. View looking down the street with the man facing the camera.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marshall Hostetler - Associated with the Anna Johnson Murder</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1915/110/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1915/110/</guid>
      <description>Portrait of Marshall Hostetler standing on a sidewalk in Chicago, Illinois. Stores show windows and buildings are visible along the sidewalk. Hostetler was associated with the Anna Johnson murder case.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
See related case
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marshall Hostetler, Alice Swanson, and Marrie Johnson - Associated with the Anna Johnson Murder</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1915/108/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1915/108/</guid>
      <description>Marshall Hostetler, Alice Swanson and Marie Johnson, associated with the Anna Johnson murder case, walking on a sidewalk.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
See related case
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Men Ride Locomotive</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1915/81/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1915/81/</guid>
      <description>Image of a Chicago, Milwaukee and St. Paul Railroad locomotive on the tracks with some men standing alongside it and some men visible standing on top of it. This image was taken in Chicago.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miss Annie Hinrichsen and Police Captain Talk to Girl Prisoner</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1915/89/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1915/89/</guid>
      <description>Image of Miss Annie Hinrichsen of the State Board of Charities and Police Captain Thomas Meagher standing by a jail cell and talking with a girl prisoner at the Des Plaines Street police station in Chicago.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motorboat on Waterway</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1915/82/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1915/82/</guid>
      <description>Image of motorboat with passengers moving along a waterway near an industrial area in Chicago, Illinois, during a street car strike.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mrs. Charles Petzel and Son, Family of Murdered Mailman Charles Petzel</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1915/123/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1915/123/</guid>
      <description>Group portrait of Mrs. Charles Petzel and her infant son, Charles Petzel, Jr., sitting in a room in Chicago, Illinois. Her husband was murdered by George (Peanut) Natzke.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
See related case
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mrs. Frank Rattray Lillie</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1915/387/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1915/387/</guid>
      <description>Mrs. Frank Rattray Lillie, sitting in a police station
Chicago Daily News, Inc., photographer.
Created/Published 1915 Dec. 17
Summary Portrait of Mrs. Frank Rattray Lillie, sitting in a police station in Chicago, Illinois. She is sitting in a chair, but several men are sitting on benches, facing the other direction, in the room. Her husband was a professor at the University of Chicago, and she was involved in the garment workers&amp;rsquo; union.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mrs. Lucy E. Parsons, Arrested During Protest at Hull House</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1915/280/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1915/280/</guid>
      <description>Three-quarter length portrait of Mrs. Lucy E. Parsons, arrested for rioting during an unemployment protest at Hull House in Chicago, Illinois. Mrs. Parsons is also the widow of Albert Parsons, one of the men hanged for complicity in the Haymarket affair.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
See related case
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Murder of William Weil</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1915/355/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1915/355/</guid>
      <description>Police Captain Smith and coroner&amp;rsquo;s physician Dr. Joseph Springer looking at William Weil&amp;rsquo;s body lying on the floor in a rear room of his store
Chicago Daily News, Inc., photographer.
Created/Published 1915
Summary Image of Police Capt. Smith and coroner&amp;rsquo;s physician Dr. Joseph Springer looking at William Weil&amp;rsquo;s body lying on the floor in a rear room of his store in Chicago, Illinois. Text on negative: Weil murder, back room.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Olive Waldeck</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1915/376/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1915/376/</guid>
      <description>Olive Waldeck, standing in a police station
Chicago Daily News, Inc., photographer.
Created/Published 1915
Summary Portrait of Olive Waldeck, standing in a police station in Chicago, Illinois.
Notes This photonegative taken by a Chicago Daily News photographer may have been published in the newspaper.
Cite as: DN-0065172, Chicago Daily News negatives collection, Chicago Historical Society. Reproduction Number: DN-0065172 Digital ID: ichicdn n065172
��������
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Policeman Jason Walston</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1915/432/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1915/432/</guid>
      <description>Policeman, Jason Walston, looking to his left and sitting in a room
Chicago Daily News, Inc., photographer.
Created/Published 1915 Oct. 5
Summary Portrait of Jason Walston, a policeman, looking slightly to his left, and sitting in a room in Chicago, Illinois. Walston turned in Frank Lombardi for trying to bribe him during a trial.
Notes An image related to this photonegative taken by a Chicago Daily News photographer was published in the newspaper on October 5, 1915.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Russell Pethrick (front)</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1915/352/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1915/352/</guid>
      <description>Coppersmith murder case, Russell Pethrick, accused murderer, sitting in an Englewood police station, looking up and to right
Chicago Daily News, Inc., photographer.
Created/Published 1915 May 17
Summary Half-length portrait of looking up and to the right of Russell Pethrick sitting in a police station in the Englewood community area of Chicago, Illinois. Pethrick was the accused murderer of Mrs. Ella Coppersmith and her infant son, John. Pethrick said he killed Mrs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Russell Pethrick (side)</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1915/353/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1915/353/</guid>
      <description>Coppersmith murder case, Russell Pethrick, accused murderer, sitting in an Englewood police station, head and shoulders
Chicago Daily News, Inc., photographer.
Created/Published 1915 May 17
Summary Head and shoulders portrait of Russell Pethrick sitting in a police station in the Englewood community area of Chicago, Illinois. Pethrick was the accused murderer of Mrs. Ella Coppersmith and her infant son, John. Pethrick said he killed Mrs. Coppersmith after a quarrel about payment for the meat he had delivered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Russell Pethrick (sitting)</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1915/373/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1915/373/</guid>
      <description>Coppersmith murder case, Russell Pethrick, accused murderer, sitting in an Englewood police station, with legs crossed
Chicago Daily News, Inc., photographer.
Created/Published 1915 May 17
Summary Three-quarter length portrait, with legs crossed, of Russell Pethrick sitting in a police station in the Englewood community area of Chicago, Illinois. Pethrick was the accused murderer of Mrs. Ella Coppersmith and her infant son, John. Pethrick said he killed Mrs. Coppersmith after a quarrel about payment for the meat he had delivered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sheriff Whittaker</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1915/404/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1915/404/</guid>
      <description>Sheriff Whittaker of Lake County, Indiana, standing in a field
Chicago Daily News, Inc., photographer.
Created/Published ca. 1915 Nov. 2.
Summary Full-length portrait of Sheriff Whittaker of Lake County, Indiana, standing in a field.
Notes This photonegative taken by a Chicago Daily News photographer may have been published in the newspaper.
Cite as: DN-0065358, Chicago Daily News negatives collection, Chicago Historical Society. Reproduction Number: DN-0065358 Digital ID: ichicdn n065358
��������</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Suicide Victim, Charles H. Johnston&#39;s (Secretary of United Brick and Clay Worker&#39;s Union) Home</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1915/120/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1915/120/</guid>
      <description>Exterior view of home of Charles H. Johnston, secretary of the United Brick and Clay Workers&amp;rsquo; Union. Police believed Johnston committed suicide. 2230 Kenilworth Avenue in Chicago.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Joseph Carsello Family, Bomb Explosion Survivors</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1915/115/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1915/115/</guid>
      <description>Group portrait of Joseph Carsello and family, involved in a bomb explosion in their home at 846 South Miller Street in the Near West Side community area of Chicago, Illinois. Left to right are John, Domenica (mother), James (baby), Joseph (father), Florence, and Tony (standing). The family survived the explosion with minimum injuries, although much damage was done to the home and attached family store.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>William Weil, Murder Victim</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1915/132/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1915/132/</guid>
      <description>Image of Police Capt. Smith and coroner&amp;rsquo;s physician Dr. Joseph Springer looking at William Weil&amp;rsquo;s body lying on the floor in a rear room of his store in Chicago, Illinois. Text on negative: Weil murder, back room.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
See related case
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Women At Work in Joliet Penitentiary</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1915/189/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1915/189/</guid>
      <description>Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>