<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Timeline of the City&#39;s History: 1904 on Homicide in Chicago 1870-1930</title>
    <link>/historical/timeline/1904/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Timeline of the City&#39;s History: 1904 on Homicide in Chicago 1870-1930</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/historical/timeline/1904/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bate Auto Murder Mystery</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1904/33/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1904/33/</guid>
      <description>Image of an automobile, no. 278, parked on a street in front of a garage door at Canary&amp;rsquo;s Garage with a man standing nearby in Chicago, Illinois. The car was found in Lemont, Illinois with its murdered chauffeur, Mr. John William Bate, Jr. The resulting murder investigation was known as either the Bate Auto Murder Mystery, or the Dove Case after the suspected murderer, Mr. Dove.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bate Auto Murder Mystery</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1904/34/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1904/34/</guid>
      <description>View of a man or boy standing on the road leading to a house in Lemont, Illinois, where John William Bate, Jr., a chauffeur for Canary&amp;rsquo;s Garage, was found murdered. The resulting murder investigation was known as either the Bate Auto Murder Mystery, or the Dove Case after the suspected murderer Mr. Dove.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
See related case
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bridewell Prison Stone Quarries</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1904/69/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1904/69/</guid>
      <description>View of men working in the Bridewell Prison stone quarries, at South California Avenue and West 26th Street, in the Little Village community area in Chicago.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chinese Girl and Boy in Traditional Dress</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1904/74/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1904/74/</guid>
      <description>Portrait of a Chinese girl and boy in traditional dress standing next to each other on a chair surrounded by various objects, furnishings and textiles. The image was taken as part of a Chinese New Year celebration in Chicago.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Image of a Boy with a Cigarette During the 1904 Stockyards Strike</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1904/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1904/4/</guid>
      <description>Image of a boy with a cigarette during the 1904 Stockyards Strike in the New City community area of Chicago.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Iroquois Theater Fire Investigation</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1904/359/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1904/359/</guid>
      <description>Iroquois Theater fire investigation, Mayor Carter H. Harrison testifying before the speaker&amp;rsquo;s rostrum in the City Hall council chamber, looking up
Chicago Daily News, Inc., photographer.
Created/Published 1904 Jan
Summary Image of Mayor Carter H. Harrison, looking up while testifying during the Iroquois Theater fire inquest. Mayor Harrison is standing before the speaker&amp;rsquo;s rostrum in the City Hall council chamber in Chicago, Illinois.
Notes This photonegative taken by a Chicago Daily News photographer may have been published in the newspaper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jack Williams, Arrested with Bomb</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1904/42/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1904/42/</guid>
      <description>Half-length portrait of Jack Williams, who was arrested with a bomb on his person, sitting in a chair in a room in Chicago.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>