<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>About on Homicide in Chicago 1870-1930</title>
    <link>/about/</link>
    <description>Recent content in About on Homicide in Chicago 1870-1930</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bibliography</title>
      <link>/about/bibliography/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/bibliography/</guid>
      <description>Archives, Court Records and Sources of Original Documents Official Records and Reports, Other Sources of Data and Historical Documents Previous Publications Using Cases from the Chicago Police Files Contemporaneous Accounts and Early Academic Studies Special Topics, Monographs, other Academic Sources and Historical Accounts Special Topics: Blacks in Chicago Newspapers and the Press The Police Other Accounts of Organized Crime and Al Capone  Archives, Court Records and Sources of Original Documents Administrative Office of the Illinois Courts, “A Short History of the Illinois Judicial Systems,” [Administrative Office of Illinois Courts, 1968, reprinted, 1990] Ch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact Us</title>
      <link>/about/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/contact/</guid>
      <description>This website was conceived as an open-ended project and, as such, we welcome the submission of material from both the academic world and the general public; as well as requests for information on the site&amp;rsquo;s content, design and development.
For our academic audience, please direct inquiries or requests to Leigh B. Bienen, Northwestern University School of Law, or her Faculty Assistant, Juana Haskin.
If, for example, you possess photographs or newspaper clippings or other archival material regarding a person or event recorded in this data set or archives, we welcome the opportunity to add information to this web site and to our data set.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Copyright</title>
      <link>/about/copyright/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/copyright/</guid>
      <description>This Web site and its information, content, and services are protected by copyright and intellectual property laws. Copyright is in the name of Leigh B. Bienen and the Northwestern University School of Law. This Web site is for educational use and distribution with appropriate attribution and credit. Neither the Web site nor its content is to be used for any commercial purpose. You may not modify, publish, transmit, participate in the transfer or sale of works or images, or exploit any of the content, in whole or in part, of this Web site for any commercial purpose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Credits</title>
      <link>/about/credits/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/credits/</guid>
      <description>Principals
 Leigh B. Bienen, Project Director Senior Lecturer, School of Law, Northwestern University Juana Haskin, Project Co-ordinator Faculty Assistant, School of Law, Northwestern University Dennis Glenn, Project Manager Assistant Dean for Distributed Education, School of Communication, Northwestern University Mark Swindle, Designer/Information Architect Senior Designer, School of Education and Social Policy, Northwestern University  Northwestern University School of Law
 David Van Zandt, Dean Chris Simoni Associate Dean for Library and Information Services Marcia Lehr Faculty Services Librarian Pegeen Bassett Documents Librarian Angie Roberts Copy Center Willie Watkins Copy Center  Northwestern University School of Communication</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distributed Learning Center</title>
      <link>/about/dlc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/dlc/</guid>
      <description>Professor Bienen approached us on the basis of our expertise in the design and creation of interactive learning environments and websites such as The Last Expression, The School of Communication website, The Oyez Project: U.S. Supreme Court Multimedia Database, and the Distributed Learning Initiative.
Our challenge was in how to make this dataset come alive. Two of the approaches we took toward accomplishing this were, first, to develop the scripting that would allow the website&amp;rsquo;s users to interact with the dataset&amp;hellip;how could we, for example, let someone do a search for a family member from several generations past who was a victim of a homicide, or to pull up all the cases involving capital punishment?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FAQs</title>
      <link>/about/faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/faq/</guid>
      <description>The Project How long did developing the Chicago historical homicide database take? There were three steps to creating the database: converting the records into electronic form, feeding the information into the database, and making the database accessible to users. The conversion of 11,400 records into electronic form took nine months and consisted of one person retyping the records into Microsoft Word.
The next step was even more time consuming and involved numerous people over five years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leigh Bienen</title>
      <link>/about/leigh-bienen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/leigh-bienen/</guid>
      <description>Leigh B. Bienen is a senior lecturer at Northwestern University School of Law and a criminal defense attorney whose areas of expertise include capital punishment, sex crimes, and rape reform legislation. She has taught law at the Woodrow Wilson School of Princeton University, at the University of Pennsylvania School of Law and the University of California (Berkeley) School of Law. She is licensed to practice law in Illinois, New Jersey, Pennsylvania, New York, and D.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links to Related Sites</title>
      <link>/about/links/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/links/</guid>
      <description>Visit Our Companion Websites:     Florence Kelley in Chicago 1891-1899 Florence Kelley was the first woman factory inspector in the United States, appointed in Illinois by Governor John Peter Altgeld in 1893. A resident of Hull House, and a reformer – who refused to be associated with any political party–Florence Kelley lived in Chicago from 1891 until 1899, leading and participating in a variety of projects. These included: a wage and ethnicity census of the slums and tenements in Chicago; the reporting of cases and contagion in the smallpox epidemic of 1893; the enforcement of the universal primary education laws, and, most importantly, enforcing the provisions of the Illinois Factory Inspections Law of 1893.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terms of Use for Homicide In Chicago, 1870-1930</title>
      <link>/about/terms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/terms/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Homicide in Chicago, 1870-1930. The following are the Terms of Use (these &amp;ldquo;Terms&amp;rdquo;) that govern use of the Homicide in Chicago, 1870-1930 website (the &amp;ldquo;Site&amp;rdquo;). By using or visiting the Site, you expressly agree to be bound by these Terms and to follow these Terms and all applicable laws and regulations governing the Site. Homicide in Chicago, 1870-1930 reserves the right to change these Terms at any time, effective immediately upon posting on the Site.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>