<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Legals on Homicide in Chicago 1870-1930</title>
    <link>/legal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Legals on Homicide in Chicago 1870-1930</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/legal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Accidents</title>
      <link>/legal/accidents/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/legal/accidents/</guid>
      <description>Deaths attributed to accidental shooting occur regularly throughout this set of cases. Some cases involve children, some involve quarrels in saloons or bars, or circumstances of domestic violence.
Gun accidents and gun deaths are typically recorded by the police as part of their regular record keeping (JCLC p.547-548, JCLC p.516). Records concerning the regulation of firearms during this period are contradictory, and the subject of academic research and debate (Article by Greg S.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anti-Corruption Campaigns</title>
      <link>/legal/corruption/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/legal/corruption/</guid>
      <description>Lieutenant Augustus White   Captain Nicholas Hunt   Healey Corruption Case   Policeman Jason Walston   Lieutenant Augustus White   The history of the Chicago police and city government during this period is a story of periodic efforts at reform, followed by elections which put back in power corrupt politicians and officers of the law. The police department was under the authority of the Mayor, and the appointment or retention of the Chief of Police for Chicago was one of the first and most important political acts of a new administration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Capital Punishment</title>
      <link>/legal/capital/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/legal/capital/</guid>
      <description>Capital punishment, or the death penalty, was the legal punishment for murder during this entire period. Yet a small proportion of those convicted of murder were sentenced to death, and a smaller proportion of those were actually executed. During this entire time capital punishment was a politically charged issue, with periodic calls for its abolition. Juries imposed the death sentence under the law, but judges controlled the conduct of trial and had the authority to modify or overrule the jury&amp;rsquo;s sentence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Capital Punishment Cases</title>
      <link>/legal/capital-cases/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/legal/capital-cases/</guid>
      <description>hanged at Philadelphia for murder of Pitzel, Confessed to many murders in Chicago.        July 27, 1919 Wilkinson, Jannet - Age 6 - Choked to death and body hidden under coal in basement of 114 E. Superior St., by Thomas Fitzgerald, who, on 7&amp;frasl;28 was held by the Coroner. 28 Pct. 9/23/19 - Sentenced to hang 10/17/19 - Crowe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Criminology</title>
      <link>/legal/criminology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/legal/criminology/</guid>
      <description>Photos of Northwestern University Law School facilities, Loop location, circa 1900. Click on images to view full-sized versions.
Criminology - the study of crime, the police, the judicial system and the interaction of these institutions within the society - began to be a serious academic enterprise in Chicago during this period. The city, its crimes, its police, and its social institutions became the laboratory for the city&amp;rsquo;s study of itself, and resulted in the production of a reservoir of important data, commentary and contemporaneous accounts concerning this period.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gambling</title>
      <link>/legal/gambling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/legal/gambling/</guid>
      <description>Police in America (1971) pages 9-12</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Judges</title>
      <link>/legal/judges/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/legal/judges/</guid>
      <description>Judges (Judge Lyle and Judge McKinley) were elected throughout this period, and their election necessarily involved them in the ward politics of the period. Accounts of changes in the judiciary parallel demographic changes, and changes in the distribution of political power.
The process of electing judges and the influence of ward politicians upon judges and the judicial process is described in detail by a former Chief Judge of the Cook County Court.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Labor Laws</title>
      <link>/legal/labor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/legal/labor/</guid>
      <description>Please visit our companion site – The Life &amp;amp; Times of Florence Kelley in Chicago 1891-1899 - which focuses on the work of Florence Kelley, the first woman factory inspector in the United States, and appointed in Illinois by Governor John Peter Altgeld in 1893. A resident of Hull House, and a reformer – who refused to be associated with any political party–Florence Kelley lived in Chicago from 1891 until 1899, leading and participating in a variety of projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lives of Lawyers</title>
      <link>/legal/lawyers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/legal/lawyers/</guid>
      <description>        William P. Black Clarence Darrow  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Murder-Suicides</title>
      <link>/legal/murder/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/legal/murder/</guid>
      <description>In a number of these cases the defendant killed his wife, or wife and children, and then killed himself, or attempted to kill himself. And there are some cases where a woman killed her husband or her children, and then killed herself or attempted to kill herself.
View all homicides in which circumstances included suicide
View video of Cynthia Grant Bowman, author of Wife Murder in Chicago: 1910-1930
View video of Michelle Oberman, author of Understanding Infanticide in Context: Mothers Who Kill, 1870-1930 and Today</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prostitution</title>
      <link>/legal/prostitution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/legal/prostitution/</guid>
      <description>Prostitution was never legal in Chicago. The notorious Levee district, ostensibly closed down in 1911 - 1912, was a place where brothels, gambling houses, and illegal saloons were publicly allowed to exist, tolerated or ignored by the police, the city government and the citizenry. Organized crime controlled large and highly profitable illegal enterprises in this district and elsewhere, paying off police and politicians. Highly publicized, periodic efforts at reform had little impact.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Laws</title>
      <link>/legal/laws/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/legal/laws/</guid>
      <description>This collection of statutes, cases and other legal documents relate to subjects and topics addressed in this web site. They are arranged chronologically, rather than by subject.
 Illinois Homicide Statute 1871 &amp;ldquo;Lehr and Wehr&amp;rdquo; Act 1879 Chicago Concealed Weapons Law 1881 Presser v. Illinois 116 U.S.252 (1886) Illinois Juvenile Court Act 1899 Illinois Child Labor Act 1903 Municipal Court of Chicago Act - 1906 Chicago Concealed Weapons Law 1905 U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wife Murder</title>
      <link>/legal/wife-murder/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/legal/wife-murder/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>