<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Timeline of the City&#39;s History: 1916 on Homicide in Chicago 1870-1930</title>
    <link>/historical/timeline/1916/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Timeline of the City&#39;s History: 1916 on Homicide in Chicago 1870-1930</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/historical/timeline/1916/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Charles Mellon</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1916/180/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1916/180/</guid>
      <description>Image of Charles Mellon, sitting in a courtroom in Chicago, Illinois. Text on the image reads, &amp;lsquo;Detective Charles Mellon in Matter Case.&amp;rsquo; Mellon was the alleged illicit lover of Mrs. Anna Matters, who was on trial for buying a baby in order to make a claim on her late husband&amp;rsquo;s estate.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frederick Bruce Johnstone</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1916/384/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1916/384/</guid>
      <description>President of the Municipal Voters League, Frederick Bruce Johnstone, sitting in a room
Chicago Daily News, Inc., photographer.
Created/Published 1916 Mar. 23
Summary Portrait of Frederick Bruce Johnstone, President of the Municipal Voters League, sitting in a room in Chicago, Illinois. The League urged voters to vote based on each individual candidate, not on party affiliation. The League was opposed by Mayor Thompson.
Notes This photonegative taken by a Chicago Daily News photographer was published in the newspaper on March 23, 1916.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Healey Corruption Case</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1916/430/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1916/430/</guid>
      <description>Healey corruption case, crowded municipal court room, presided over by Judge Olson, judge is visible on right side of image
Chicago Daily News, Inc., photographer.
Created/Published 1916 Oct. 19
Summary Image of the crowded municipal court room of Judge Olson, during the trial of Chief of Police Charles Healey, who was involved in corruption at City Hall. Those in attendance include: Healey, Maclay Hoyne, Cook County State&amp;rsquo;s Attorney, Police Captain Madden, Captain Morgan Collins, Captain Alcock, Corporation Counsel Ettelson, Attorney John J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Health Commissioner Examining Phials of Poison</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1916/18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1916/18/</guid>
      <description>Image of City of Chicago Health Commissioner Dr. John Dill Robertson examining phials of poisons in anarchist Jean Crones&amp;rsquo; room at 22nd Street and Prairie Avenue in the Near South Side community area of Chicago, Illinois. Crones was an assistant chef at the University Club, and disappeared after 100 banquet attendees at a reception for Archbishop Mundelein were poisoned with arsenic.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Herbert Updike</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1916/354/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1916/354/</guid>
      <description>Updike murder plot, Herbert Updike sitting in Oak Park, Illinois police station
Chicago Daily News, Inc., photographer.
Created/Published 1916 Jan. 22
Summary Portrait of Herbert Updike, sitting in the county police station in Oak Park, Illinois.
Notes This photonegative taken by a Chicago Daily News photographer was published in the newspaper on January 22, 1916.
Cite as: DN-0065653, Chicago Daily News negatives collection, Chicago Historical Society. Reproduction Number: DN-0065653 Digital ID: ichicdn n065653</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>John Allegrini, Friend of the Anarchist Jean Crone</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1916/16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1916/16/</guid>
      <description>Portrait of John Allegrini, friend of the anarchist Jean Crone, sitting in the county jail in Chicago, Illinois. Crone was accused of poisoning the soup at a banquet for Archbishop Mundelein. He fled to New York.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jury Members of the Matters Case</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1916/181/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1916/181/</guid>
      <description>Members of the Matters jury standing on a sidewalk outside the County Building.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Margaret Sanger, Social Reformer and Founder of the Birth Control Movement</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1916/179/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1916/179/</guid>
      <description>Portrait of Margaret Sanger (1879-1966), social reformer and founder of the birth control movement in the United States, sitting in a room in Chicago.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>McIntyre Murder Case</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1916/337/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1916/337/</guid>
      <description>McIntyre murder case, home of Henry McIntyre, after police raid, with crowd standing in front
Chicago Daily News, Inc., photographer.
Created/Published ca. 1916 Aug. 2.
Summary Exterior view of the home of Henry McIntyre, with a crowd standing in front. McIntyre was an African American man who went on a shooting spree, killing a policeman and three neighbors, and wounding two policeman and one neighbor. The home was located at 320 North Irving Avenue in Chicago, Illinois.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mrs. Ruth Edwards</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1916/378/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1916/378/</guid>
      <description>Mrs. Ruth Edwards, sitting with her toddler son Leontine on her lap, in the East Chicago Avenue police station
Chicago Daily News, Inc., photographer.
Created/Published 1916 Feb. 19.
Summary Group portrait of Mrs. Ruth Edwards, sitting with her toddler son Leontine on her lap, in the East Chicago Avenue police station in Chicago, Illinois. Edwards was accused trying to kill her baby.
Notes This photonegative taken by a Chicago Daily News photographer was published in the newspaper on February 19, 1916.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Police Anton Calek</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1916/408/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1916/408/</guid>
      <description>Policeman, Anton Calek, sitting in a room
Chicago Daily News, Inc., photographer.
Created/Published 1916 May 3
Summary Portrait of Anton Calek, a policeman of the East Chicago Avenue Police Station, sitting in a room in Chicago, Illinois.
Notes An article related to this photonegative taken by a Chicago Daily News photographer was published in the newspaper on May 3, 1916.
Cite as: DN-0066184, Chicago Daily News negatives collection, Chicago Historical Society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Policeman Coley Madden</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1916/433/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1916/433/</guid>
      <description>Photograph of Coley Madden, a policeman
Chicago Daily News, Inc., photographer.
Created/Published 1916 May 10
Summary Image of a photograph of Coley Madden, a policeman. Madden killed an ex-convict. This photograph was taken by Marchand of Chicago. This image was taken in Chicago, Illinois.
Notes This photonegative taken by a Chicago Daily News photographer was published in the newspaper on May 10, 1916.
Cite as: DN-0066245, Chicago Daily News negatives collection, Chicago Historical Society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Policeman John Scott</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1916/399/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1916/399/</guid>
      <description>Policeman and cartoonist, John Scott, sitting in a room
Chicago Daily News, Inc., photographer.
Created/Published ca. 1916 Mar. 11.
Summary Portrait of John E. Scott, policeman and cartoonist, sitting in a room in Chicago, Illinois.
Notes This photonegative taken by a Chicago Daily News photographer may have been published in the newspaper.
Cite as: DN-0066015, Chicago Daily News negatives collection, Chicago Historical Society. Reproduction Number: DN-0066015 Digital ID: ichicdn n066015</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sister Saint Celestine of Ottawa, Canada</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1916/182/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1916/182/</guid>
      <description>Matters case, Sister Saint Celestine of Ottawa, Canada, sitting in the witness stand in a courtroom.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Street Car Union Heads</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1916/86/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1916/86/</guid>
      <description>Group portrait of street car union heads Ed McMorrow, W. D. Mahon, Leonard Busby, William Quinlan and William Taber (left to right) sitting around a table in a room in Chicago.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>