<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Timeline of the City&#39;s History: 1902 on Homicide in Chicago 1870-1930</title>
    <link>/historical/timeline/1902/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Timeline of the City&#39;s History: 1902 on Homicide in Chicago 1870-1930</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/historical/timeline/1902/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Associated with the Bartholin Murder Case</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1902/31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1902/31/</guid>
      <description>View of men and boys (African American and White) standing on sidewalk and curb outside of a two-storied dwelling at 4310 Calumet Avenue in the Grand Boulevard community area of Chicago. The building was associated with the Bartholin murder case.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
See related case
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christmas Eve at the Salvation Army</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1902/48/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1902/48/</guid>
      <description>Image of people sitting in chairs inside a room at the Salvation Army at Christmas in Chicago. A policeman is standing in the room and facing the camera.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edwards, Involved in the Bartholin Murder Case</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1902/32/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1902/32/</guid>
      <description>Half-length portrait of Edwards, who was involved in the Bartholin murder case, sitting in a room in Chicago
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Archer Avenue Swing Bridge</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1902/39/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1902/39/</guid>
      <description>Old Archer Avenue swing bridge, looking along the exterior length of the bridge over the Chicago River and showing a horse drawn cart is going over the bridge.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sweatshop Interior</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1902/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1902/3/</guid>
      <description>Interior view of a room in Chicago in which three men are standing around a high table that has pieces of fabric on it. One of the men is wearing work clothes and the other two are wearing suits. One of the men wearing a suit is leaning over the table, writing. Two girls are sitting on opposite sides of a lower table and are sewing by hand. A stove and pipe are visible to the side of the activity in the room.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Garfield School Strike for Recess</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1902/49/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1902/49/</guid>
      <description>Image of a group of boys assembled by Garfield School during the 1902 school strike. One boy appears to be African-American. The children went on strike to demand a longer time for recess. The school was located at West 14th and South Kedzie Avenue in the North Lawndale community area of Chicago.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Women and Chidren Picking Up Coal</title>
      <link>/historical/timeline/1902/52/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/historical/timeline/1902/52/</guid>
      <description>Image of women and children picking up coal from the ground at the coal yards in Chicago. Bags and baskets of coal are lying on the ground near them.
Courtesy of the Chicago Historical Society.
Other images from this year</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>